In this Developer Basics video, we
この開発者向け 基本ビデオでは
are going to gain knowledge of the little-used or known
あまり使われていない、 あるいは知られていない
data-embed attribute of the advanced player implementation
高度なプレーヤー実装コードである data-embed属性について
code.
説明していきます。
This attribute always appears in the advanced player code,
この属性はアドバンスト・プレーヤーの コードに必ず含まれますが
but few understand its purpose.
その用途を理解している人は ほとんどいないでしょう。
The data-embed attribute is very seldom used, and therefore,
data-embed属性は滅多に 使用されることがない為、
not well understood.
よく理解されていません。
The attribute reflects parent-child relationships
この属性は、プレーヤーの 親子関係を反映した
with players.
属性になります。
Imagine if you have a website and you
もし、あなたがwebサイトを持っており、 他のプレーヤーに影響を与える
want to have a base player which influences all other players.
ベースとなるプレーヤーを 持ちたいとします。
You could set up a parent, or default, player, then
親もしくはデフォルトの プレーヤーを設定し、
make children, or embeds, of that parent.
子およびエンベッドを 作成すことが出来ます。
Changes you make to the parent player
親プレーヤーに 加えた変更は、
will be inherited by child players.
子プレーヤーに 引き継ぐことが出来ます。
Child players can modify inherited changes
子プレーヤーは、受け継いだ 変更を修正したり、
or add more player configuration.
プレーヤー設定を追加で 行うことが出来ます。
Let's look quickly at the document covering embeds.
エンベデッドに関する ドキュメントを見てみましょう。
This diagram shows the inheritance
この図は、子プレーヤーへの 継承を示したもので、
to the child players, while one child adds to the player
一方の子は プレーヤー設定を追加し、
and the other child overrides the shape
もう一方の子は 大きな再生ボタンの
of the big Play button.
形状をオーバーライドしています。
The second diagram shows the poster, the image that it
2つ目の図では、 動画再生前に表示されていた
displayed before the video plays, is changed from a field
ポスター画像を 親プレーヤーで
to a flower in the parent.
畑から花に変更したものです。
Note that the change is inherited by both children.
なお、この変更は両方の 子に継承されています。
Lastly, you can tell if a player is
最後に、プレーヤーが 親であるか子であるかは、
a parent or child by the value for the data-embed attribute.
data-embed属性の 値で判断することが出来ます。
If the value of the attribute is default,
属性値が defaultの場合
the player is a parent.
プレーヤーが親であることを示します。
Note that in player embed speak, the player can be a parent
また、プレーヤーは親であっても、
but not have any children.
子を持たないことも出来ます。
If the value of data-embed is not default,
data-embedの値が defaultでない場合、
it reflects the ID of the parent player.
親プレーヤーの IDが反映されます。
Note that the data-player attribute, the actual player
なお、実際のプレーヤーIDである data-player属性は、
ID, is the same in both cases.
どちらも同じ値になります。
One other insight into using embeds,
もう一点、エンベッドを 使用する際の注意点として、
and that is child players do not appear in Studio.
子プレーヤーがStudioに 表示されないことが挙げられます。
If you wish to alter them in some way,
何らかの方法で 変更したい場合は、
you must use the player management API to do so.
プレーヤー管理APIを 使用する必要があります。
Now you've joined the select club
これで、あなたも data-embed player属性を
of those who actually understand the data-embed player
理解している人たちの
attribute.
仲間入りが出来ました。